Question, what is polymerization?
Hey everyone and welcome.
Today we're tackling a fascinating question.
What exactly is 20-30 polymerization?
It might sound like a complicated term,
but the basic idea is quite simple.
So let's break it down together.
Polymerization is a chemical process
in which many small molecules, which we call monomers,
combine to form a much larger molecule known as a polymer.
Think of it like building with Legos,
each individual brick is a monomer.
And when you connect them all together,
you create a larger, more complex structure,
which would be the polymer.
Now there are different ways this process can occur.
And we can broadly categorize them into two main types.
Addition and condensation polymerization.
Addition polymerization involves monomers
simply joining together without producing any byproducts,
kind of like snapping Legos directly onto each other.
On the other hand, condensation polymerization
involves the elimination of small molecules,
such as water or hydrogen chloride during the reaction.
A great example of polymerization in action
is when it the molecules polymerized to form polythene,
which is a very common type of plastic
that you probably interact with every day.
Essentially polymerization is all about linking
simple units into long repeating chains.
And this allows us to create materials
with incredibly varied and useful properties
from plastics and fibers to resins polymerization,
plays a vital role in creating so many of the materials
we use in our lives.
And pretty amazing, right?